<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-10-04T11:37:43+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">DeFacto</title><subtitle>Design Automation for Smart Factories</subtitle><author><name>Michele Lora</name></author><entry><title type="html">A DeFacto paper has been accepted at IROS 2023</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/iros2023/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A DeFacto paper has been accepted at IROS 2023" /><published>2023-09-01T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2023-09-01T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/IROS2023</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/iros2023/">&lt;p&gt;A paper titled &lt;strong&gt;Task Assignment, Scheduling, and Motion Planning for Automated 
Warehouses for Million Product Workloads&lt;/strong&gt;,
authored by &lt;em&gt;Christopher Leet&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Chanwook Oh&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Michele Lora&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Sven Koenig&lt;/em&gt;, 
and &lt;em&gt;Pierluigi Nuzzo&lt;/em&gt; has been accepted at the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://https://ieee-iros.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;2023 IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems 
(IROS 2023)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-justify text-justify&quot;&gt;In this work, we address the Warehouse Servicing Problem
(WSP) in automated warehouses, which use teams of mobile
robots to move products from shelves to packaging stations.
Given a list of products, the WSP amounts to finding a motion
plan which brings every product on the list from a shelf to a
packaging station within a given time limit. The WSP consists
of four subproblems, namely, deciding where to source and
deposit a product (task formulation), who should transport
each product (task assignment) and when (scheduling) and how
(motion planning). These problems are NP-Hard individually
and made more challenging by their interdependence. The
difficulty of the WSP is compounded by the scale of automated
warehouses, which use teams of hundreds of agents to transport
thousands of products. In this paper, we present Contractbased Cyclic Motion Planning (CCMP), a novel contract-based
methodology for solving the WSP at scale. CCMP decomposes a
warehouse into a set of traffic system components. By assigning
each component a contract which describes the traffic flows it
can support, CCMP can generate a traffic flow which satisfies
a given WSP instance. CCMP then uses a novel motion planner
to transform this traffic flow into a motion plan for a team of
robots. Evaluation shows that CCMP can solve WSP instances
taken from real industrial scenarios with up to 1 million
products while outperforming other methodologies for solving
the WSP by up to 2.9×.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-justify&quot;&gt;A pre-print of the paper is available &lt;a href=&quot;pdf/Leet_IROS23_2023.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Michele Lora</name></author><category term="Output" /><summary type="html">A paper titled Task Assignment, Scheduling, and Motion Planning for Automated Warehouses for Million Product Workloads, authored by Christopher Leet, Chanwook Oh, Michele Lora, Sven Koenig, and Pierluigi Nuzzo has been accepted at the 2023 IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS 2023).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A DeFacto paper has been accepted at DDECS 2023</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/ddecs2023/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A DeFacto paper has been accepted at DDECS 2023" /><published>2023-03-08T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-03-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/DDECS2023</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/ddecs2023/">&lt;p class=&quot;text-justify&quot;&gt;A paper titled &lt;strong&gt;Split-Et-Impera: A Framework for the Design of
Distributed Deep Learning Applications&lt;/strong&gt;,
authored by &lt;em&gt;Luigi Capogrosso&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Federico Cunico&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Michele Lora&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Marco
Cristani&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Franco Fummi&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Davide Quaglia&lt;/em&gt;
has been accepted at the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://ddecs2023.taltech.ee/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;26th International Symposium on Design and Diagnostics of Electronic Circuits and Systems 
(DDECS 2023)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-justify&quot;&gt;Many recent pattern recognition applications rely on
complex distributed architectures in which sensing and computational nodes 
interact together through a communication network.
Deep neural networks (DNNs) play an important role in this
scenario, furnishing powerful decision mechanisms, at the price
of a high computational effort. Consequently, powerful state-of-
the-art DNNs frequently are split over various computational
nodes, e.g., a first part stays on an embedded device and the
rest on a server. Deciding where to split a DNN is a challenge
in itself, making the design of deep learning applications even
more complicated. Therefore, this paper proposes Split-Et-Impera, a novel
and practical framework that i) determines the set of the
best-split points of a neural network based on deep network
interpretability principles without performing a tedious try-and-
test approach, ii) performs a communication-aware simulation for
the rapid evaluation of different neural network rearrangements,
and iii) suggests the best match between the quality of service
requirements of the application and the performance in terms of
accuracy and latency time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-justify&quot;&gt;A pre-print of the paper is available &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/2303.12524&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Michele Lora</name></author><category term="Output" /><summary type="html">A paper titled Split-Et-Impera: A Framework for the Design of Distributed Deep Learning Applications, authored by Luigi Capogrosso, Federico Cunico, Michele Lora, Marco Cristani, Franco Fummi, and Davide Quaglia has been accepted at the 26th International Symposium on Design and Diagnostics of Electronic Circuits and Systems (DDECS 2023) Many recent pattern recognition applications rely on complex distributed architectures in which sensing and computational nodes interact together through a communication network. Deep neural networks (DNNs) play an important role in this scenario, furnishing powerful decision mechanisms, at the price of a high computational effort. Consequently, powerful state-of- the-art DNNs frequently are split over various computational nodes, e.g., a first part stays on an embedded device and the rest on a server. Deciding where to split a DNN is a challenge in itself, making the design of deep learning applications even more complicated. Therefore, this paper proposes Split-Et-Impera, a novel and practical framework that i) determines the set of the best-split points of a neural network based on deep network interpretability principles without performing a tedious try-and- test approach, ii) performs a communication-aware simulation for the rapid evaluation of different neural network rearrangements, and iii) suggests the best match between the quality of service requirements of the application and the performance in terms of accuracy and latency time. A pre-print of the paper is available here.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A DeFacto paper has been accepted at DATE 2023</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/date2023/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A DeFacto paper has been accepted at DATE 2023" /><published>2022-11-17T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-11-17T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/DATE2023</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/date2023/">&lt;p class=&quot;text-justify&quot;&gt;The paper titled &lt;strong&gt;Co-Design of Topology, Scheduling, and Path Planning in 
Automated Warehouses&lt;/strong&gt;, authored by &lt;em&gt;Christopher Leet&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Chanwook Oh&lt;/em&gt;, 
          &lt;em&gt;Michele Lora&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Sven Koenig&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Pierluigi Nuzzo&lt;/em&gt;, 
has been accepted at the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://date-conference.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;2023 IEEE/ACM Design Automation and Test in Europe&lt;/a&gt;
that will be held in Antwerp, 17 - 19 April 2023.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-justify&quot;&gt;In the accepted paper, we address the warehouse servicing problem (WSP) in 
automated warehouses, which 
use teams of mobile agents to bring products from shelves to packing stations. 
Given a list of products, the WSP amounts to finding a plan for a team of agents 
which brings every product on the list to a station within a given timeframe. 
The WSP consists of four subproblems, concerning what tasks to perform 
(task formulation), who will perform them (task allocation), and when 
(scheduling) and how (path planning) to perform them. 
These subproblems are NP-hard individually and become more challenging in 
combination. The difficulty of the WSP is compounded by the scale of automated 
warehouses, which frequently use teams of hundreds of agents. In this paper, we 
present a methodology that can solve the WSP at such scales. We introduce a 
novel, contract-based design framework which decomposes an automated warehouse 
into traffic system components. By assigning each of these components a contract
describing the traffic flows it can support, we can synthesize a traffic flow 
satisfying a given WSP instance. Component-wise search-based path planning is 
then used to transform this traffic f low into a plan for discrete agents in a 
modular way. Evaluation shows that this methodology can solve WSP instances on 
real automated warehouses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-justify&quot;&gt;A pre-print of the paper is available 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/2303.01448&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Michele Lora</name></author><category term="Output" /><summary type="html">The paper titled Co-Design of Topology, Scheduling, and Path Planning in Automated Warehouses, authored by Christopher Leet, Chanwook Oh, Michele Lora, Sven Koenig, and Pierluigi Nuzzo, has been accepted at the 2023 IEEE/ACM Design Automation and Test in Europe that will be held in Antwerp, 17 - 19 April 2023.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A DeFacto paper has been accepted at ICCAD 2022</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/iccad2022/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A DeFacto paper has been accepted at ICCAD 2022" /><published>2022-08-15T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-08-15T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/ICCAD2022</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/iccad2022/">&lt;p class=&quot;text-justify&quot;&gt;The paper titled &lt;strong&gt;Quantitative Verification and Design Space Exploration Under
Uncertainty with Parametric Stochastic Contracts&lt;/strong&gt;, 
authored by &lt;em&gt;Chanwook Oh&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Michele Lora&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Pierluigi Nuzzo&lt;/em&gt;, 
has been accepted at the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://iccad.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;2022 IEEE International Conference on Computer-aided Design 
(ICCAD)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-justify&quot;&gt;This paper proposes an automated framework for quantitative verification and 
design space exploration of cyber-physical systems in the presence of 
uncertainty, leveraging assume-guarantee con- tracts expressed in Stochastic 
Signal Temporal Logic (StSTL). We introduce quantitative semantics for StSTL 
and formulations of the quantitative verification and design space exploration 
problems as bi-level optimization problems. We show that these optimization 
problems can be effectively solved for a class of stochastic systems and a 
fragment of bounded-time StSTL formulas. Our algorithm searches for partitions 
of the upper-level design space such that the solutions of the lower-level 
problems satisfy the upper-level constraints. A set of optimal parameter values 
are then selected within these partitions. We illustrate the effectiveness of 
our framework on the design of a multi-sensor perception system and an 
automatic cruise control system.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Michele Lora</name></author><category term="Output" /><summary type="html">The paper titled Quantitative Verification and Design Space Exploration Under Uncertainty with Parametric Stochastic Contracts, authored by Chanwook Oh, Michele Lora and Pierluigi Nuzzo, has been accepted at the 2022 IEEE International Conference on Computer-aided Design (ICCAD)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A DeFacto paper has been accepted at ISIE 2022</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/isie2022/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A DeFacto paper has been accepted at ISIE 2022" /><published>2022-02-19T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-02-19T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/ISIE2022</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/isie2022/">&lt;p class=&quot;text-justify&quot;&gt;The paper titled &lt;strong&gt;A Hierarchical Modeling Approach to Improve Scheduling of 
Manufacturing Processes&lt;/strong&gt;, authored by &lt;em&gt;Sebastiano Gaiardelli&lt;/em&gt;, 
&lt;em&gt;Stefano Spellini&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Michele Lora&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Franco Fummi&lt;/em&gt;, has been accepted at the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ieee-isie2022.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;2022 IEEE International Symposium on 
Industrial Electronics (ISIE)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-justify&quot;&gt;Timely response to sudden production events and requirements shifts
is a key feature of Industry 4.0. It requires
techniques to manipulate and optimize the production processes,
and components providing an high degree of reconfigurability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-justify&quot;&gt;To acknowledge to such demands, this paper presents a 
multi-level and hierarchical approach to manufacturing processes modeling. 
Models are structured to represent the production hierarchically: partitioning
recipes in a set of tasks, allocated to 
machines’ manufacturing services and expressed as a sequence of elementary actions.
Then, we propose a run-time scheduling algorithm able to exploit the novel
structure given to knowledge by the proposed modeling approach.
The algorithm aims at minimizing the makespan while maximizing machines utilization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-justify&quot;&gt;We validate the contributions of this paper on a full-fledged production line. 
The modeling strategy has been implemented in SysML: a well-known systems modeling language.
The experiments show the presented model and the proposed scheduling approach 
enabling a more precise and more performing control over the manufacturing process.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Michele Lora</name></author><category term="Output" /><summary type="html">The paper titled A Hierarchical Modeling Approach to Improve Scheduling of Manufacturing Processes, authored by Sebastiano Gaiardelli, Stefano Spellini, Michele Lora and Franco Fummi, has been accepted at the 2022 IEEE International Symposium on Industrial Electronics (ISIE)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Work-in-Progress and Demo of CHASE to be presented at the 2022 CPS-IoT Week</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/iccps-wip2022/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Work-in-Progress and Demo of CHASE to be presented at the 2022 CPS-IoT Week" /><published>2022-02-16T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-02-16T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/ICCPS_WiP2022</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/iccps-wip2022/">&lt;p class=&quot;text-justify&quot;&gt;A Work-in-Progress and demo about CHASE has been accepted at the 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cpsweek.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;2022 CPS-IoT Week&lt;/a&gt;.
The contribution authored by &lt;em&gt;Michele Lora&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Pierluigi Nuzzo&lt;/em&gt;, and
titled &lt;strong&gt;A Contract-Based Requirement Engineering Framework for the
Design of Industrial Cyber-Physical Systems&lt;/strong&gt;, is inserted in the program of
the IEEE/ACM International Conference on Cyber-Physical Systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-justify&quot;&gt;This work-in-progress paper presents our current effort toward the development 
of compositional modeling formalisms and scalable algorithms for
high-assurance design of industrial cyber-physical systems, with emphasis on
smart manufacturing systems. A requirement engineering methodology is
implemented within CHASE, a software framework supporting contract-based
representations of systems and components to facilitate analysis and design
space exploration. We provide an overview of CHASE and discuss its
application to the design of a robotic arm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-justify&quot;&gt;This paper is accompanied by a poster describing the architecture of CHASE and
a demonstration of its application to the case study.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Michele Lora</name></author><category term="Output" /><summary type="html">A Work-in-Progress and demo about CHASE has been accepted at the 2022 CPS-IoT Week. The contribution authored by Michele Lora and Pierluigi Nuzzo, and titled A Contract-Based Requirement Engineering Framework for the Design of Industrial Cyber-Physical Systems, is inserted in the program of the IEEE/ACM International Conference on Cyber-Physical Systems.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A DeFacto paper has been accepted at DATE 2022</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/date2022/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A DeFacto paper has been accepted at DATE 2022" /><published>2021-11-11T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-11-11T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/DATE2022</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/date2022/">&lt;p class=&quot;text-justify&quot;&gt;The paper titled &lt;strong&gt;A Software Architecture to Control Service-Oriented 
Manufacturing Systems&lt;/strong&gt;, authored by &lt;em&gt;Sebastiano Gaiardelli&lt;/em&gt;, 
&lt;em&gt;Stefano Spellini&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Marco Panato&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Franco Fummi&lt;/em&gt;, has been accepted as
an interactive presentation at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://https://www.date-conference.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;2022 IEEE/ACM Conference on Design
Automation and Testing 
in Europe (DATE)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-justify&quot;&gt;This paper presents a software architecture extending the classical automation pyramid
to control and reconfigure flexible, service-oriented manufacturing systems.
At the Planning level, the architecture requires 
a Manufacturing Execution System (MES) consistent with the 
International Society Automation (ISA) standard.
Then, the Supervisory level is automated by introducing a novel component, called
Automation Manager. 
The new component interacts upward with the MES, and
downward with a set of servers providing access to the manufacturing
machines.
The communication with machines relies on the OPC Unified Architecture (OPC UA)
standard protocol, which allows exposing production tasks as
``services’’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-justify&quot;&gt;The proposed software architecture has been prototyped to control a real
production line, originally controlled by a commercial MES, unable to fully
exploit the flexibility provided by the case study manufacturing system.
Meanwhile, the proposed architecture is fully exploiting the production line’s
flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Michele Lora</name></author><category term="Output" /><summary type="html">The paper titled A Software Architecture to Control Service-Oriented Manufacturing Systems, authored by Sebastiano Gaiardelli, Stefano Spellini, Marco Panato, and Franco Fummi, has been accepted as an interactive presentation at the 2022 IEEE/ACM Conference on Design Automation and Testing in Europe (DATE).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Conference paper accepted at FDL 2021</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/fdl2021/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Conference paper accepted at FDL 2021" /><published>2021-07-30T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-07-30T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/FDL2021</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/fdl2021/">&lt;p class=&quot;text-justify&quot;&gt;The paper titled &lt;strong&gt;Modeling in Industry 5.0: What Is There and What Is 
Missing&lt;/strong&gt;, authored by &lt;em&gt;Sebastiano Gaiardelli&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Stefano Spellini&lt;/em&gt;, 
&lt;em&gt;Michele Lora&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Franco Fummi&lt;/em&gt;, has been accepted at the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://fdl-conference.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;2021 Forum on specification and Design Languages 
(FDL)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-justify&quot;&gt;The Industry 4.0 trend speeds up the adoption of a variety of technologies. In
modern manufacturing, system data are collected both from the field through
sensors and by exploiting complex simulations. Data analysis techniques became
crucial to build and maintain any efficient production line, while autonomous
systems and robots are the main focus of researchers and practitioners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-justify&quot;&gt;This pervasive use of artificial intelligence derived technologies pushed humans
to the border of production systems. Industry 5.0 aims at bringing the attention
back to humans in production lines while magnifying their interactions with
intelligent systems. This new trend will impact the design of future
manufacturing infrastructures, increasing their complexity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-justify&quot;&gt;Engineers will need modeling and developing tools able to capture this
complexity. In this paper, we analyze the modeling languages and tools being
used, identifying their strengths and weaknesses. Then, we propose some possible
directions to provide engineers with the expressive power needed to tackle the
challenges posed by Industry 5.0.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Michele Lora</name></author><category term="Output" /><summary type="html">The paper titled Modeling in Industry 5.0: What Is There and What Is Missing, authored by Sebastiano Gaiardelli, Stefano Spellini, Michele Lora and Franco Fummi, has been accepted at the 2021 Forum on specification and Design Languages (FDL).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Conference paper accepted at ETFA 2021</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/etfa2021/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Conference paper accepted at ETFA 2021" /><published>2021-07-07T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-07-07T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/ETFA2021</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/etfa2021/">&lt;p class=&quot;text-justify&quot;&gt;The paper titled &lt;strong&gt;Enabling Component Reuse in Model-based System Engineering of
Cyber-Physical Production Systems&lt;/strong&gt;, authored by &lt;em&gt;Stefano Spellini&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Sebastiano
Gaiardelli&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Michele Lora&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Franco Fummi&lt;/em&gt;, has been accepted at the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://2021.ieee-etfa.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;26th IEEE International Conference on Emerging Technologies and Factory 
Automation (ETFA 2021)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-justify&quot;&gt;In this work, we outline a design flow contemplating the reuse of already
existing manufacturing lines’ models, while designing novel advanced production
systems. To enable such a flow, we propose a methodology extracting
System Modeling Language (SysML) structural diagrams from AutomationML descriptions.
Then, we propose to design the system functionalities on top of the produced 
diagrams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-justify&quot;&gt;The paper shows the application of the methodology to a concrete manufacturing
line, the structure of which was originally modeled using AutomationML. To
exemplify the advantages of the methodology, we exploit the models being
generated to automatically extract a digital twin for the production system
transportation line. The resulting digital twin is compliant with a well-known
plant simulation tool.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Michele Lora</name></author><category term="Output" /><summary type="html">The paper titled Enabling Component Reuse in Model-based System Engineering of Cyber-Physical Production Systems, authored by Stefano Spellini, Sebastiano Gaiardelli, Michele Lora and Franco Fummi, has been accepted at the 26th IEEE International Conference on Emerging Technologies and Factory Automation (ETFA 2021).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DeFacto will be at IEEE/ACM DATE 2021</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/date-ubooth/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DeFacto will be at IEEE/ACM DATE 2021" /><published>2020-11-30T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-11-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/DATE-UBooth</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/date-ubooth/">&lt;p class=&quot;text-justify&quot;&gt;DeFacto will be present at the IEEE/ACM Conference on Design Automation and Test in Europe 2021.
We will present the results achieved so far at the University Booth of the Conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-justify&quot;&gt;DATE 2021 will be held virtually between the 1st and the 5th of February 2021.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Michele Lora</name></author><category term="Output" /><summary type="html">DeFacto will be present at the IEEE/ACM Conference on Design Automation and Test in Europe 2021. We will present the results achieved so far at the University Booth of the Conference.</summary></entry></feed>